Guide to the Ralph W. Tyler Papers 1932-1988
University of Chicago Library
- Series IV: Writings by Tyler
  - Subseries 3: Books, Pamphlets, and Papers
    - 1984, "How Do We Get What We Know into Common Practice?" and "How Do We Develop Skill and Artistry in Our Practice?" In Using What We Know About Teaching "Comparing the Use of Research in Other Professions with Research in Education; 'The Use of Research by Engineers' and 'Diffusion and Adoption in Educational Practice.'" In Using What We Know About Teaching "Curriculum Development and Research." In Using What We Know About Teaching (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - 1984, "Evaluation in Human Resource Development." In Joint Ventures Between Business and Higher Education; Human Resource Evaluation Introduction to No Adversary Situations; Public School Education in California and Wilson C. Riles, Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1970-1982 "System Development Foundation." In Foundations "Using Research to Improve Teaching Effectiveness." In Perspectives on Effective Teaching and the Cooperative Classroom (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - 1985, "Conditions for Effective Learning." In Education in School and Nonschool Settings "Curriculum Resources." In The International Encyclopedia of Education; Research and Studies "Education for the Twenty-first Century; The Professorate, Curricula, and Applied Technology." In Thirty-ninth Annual Proceedings of the National Conference of Academic Deans Foreword to Adapting Instruction to Individual Differences "National Assessment of Educational Progress." In The International Encyclopedia of Education; Research and Studies Conversations; 20 Years in American Education (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - 1986, The Governance of the National Assessment of Educational Progress (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - 1987, Foreword to Cooperative Education in a New Era "Marginality in Schools." Foreword to Reaching Marginal Students (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 4: Theses
    - 1923, "A New Test in High School Science." Master's thesis (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - 1927, "Statistical Methods for Utilizing Personal Judgments to Evaluate Activities for Teacher-Training Curricula." Doctoral dissertation (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - 1929, "Statistical Methods for Utilizing Personal Judgments to Evaluate Activities for Teacher-Training Curricula." In Abstracts of Theses (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 5: Reprinted Writings
    - Ac-As, "Accountability in Perspective" (1971); In Emerging Educational Issues, 1974 "Adult Education Is for Teachers, Too" (November 1947); In Wisconsin Journal of Education, November 1947; Education Digest, February 1948; Kentucky School Journal, February 1948; Texas Outlook, February 1948; Illinois Education, October 1948 "An Assessment; The Edge of the Future" (1963); In Readings on Elementary Social Studies, 1965 "Analysis of Strengths and Weaknesses" in Current Research in Science Education (1966); In Journal of Research in Science Teaching, March 1967 "Appraisal of Military Training and Experience" (1943); In Illinois Education, May 1943; Educational and Psychological Measurement, Summer 1943 "Appraising Progressive Schools" (January 1935); In Educational Method, May 1936 "Assessing Educational Achievement in the Affective Domain" (Spring 1973); In Instructional Objectives in Music, 1974 "Assessing the Progress of Education" (September 1965); In the Changing Secondary School Curriculum, 1967; Change and Secondary School Administration, 1968 "Assessing the Progress of Education" (1966); In Teachers College Record, December 1966; Contemporary Thought on Public School Curriculum, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - Co-Cu, "Conditions for Effective Learning" (September 1959); In Readings in Human Learning, 1963 "Curriculum Development Since 1900" (May 1981); In Education Digest, October 1981 "The Curriculum; Then and Now" [1957]; In Elementary School Journal, April 1957; Education Digest, October 1957; Educational Psychology, 1959; Issues in Curriculum Development, 1959; Elementary Curriculum, 1964; Testing Problems in Perspective, 1966; Contemporary Thought on Public School Curriculum, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - De-Di, "Defining and Measuring Objectives of Progressive Education" (January 1936); In Educational Research Bulletin, March 18, 1936; Readings in Educational Psychology, 1937 "Distinctive Attributes of Education for the Professions" (1952); In Social Work Journal, April 1952; National Elementary Principal, January 1968; Professional Negotiation and the Principalship, 1969; Educational Handbook for Health Personnel, 1977 "Division of Accomplishment Tests" (October 1932); In Journal of Higher Education, November 1932 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Ed-Em, "Educability and the Schools" (December 1948); In Education Digest, April 1949; Centennial, 1950; Educational Psychology, 1955; Bobbs-Merrill Reprint Series in the Social Sciences, n.d. "Education; Balancing Conditioned Response and Responsible Claims" (1971); In Managing the Planet, 1972 "Education Must Relate to a Way of Life" (1969); In Education Digest, October 1970 "Educational Adjustments Necessitated by Changing Ideological Concepts" (1941); In Elementary School Journal, September 1941; Perspectives on American Education, 1976 "Educational Measurement; A Broad Perspective" (September 1961); In Readings in Human Learning, 1963 "Educational Objectives of American Democracy" (1960); In Views on American Schooling, 1961; This Is Teaching, 1962, 1968 "Emphasize Tasks Appropriate for the School" (November 1958); In Secondary Education; Origins and Directions, 1965, 1970; Secondary Schools Today, 1965, 1969; Readings in Secondary Education; A Foundations Approach, 1968; Cream of the Kappan, 1956-1981, 1981 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Es-Ev, "Essential Aspects of Evaluation; What Is Evaluation?" (1958); In Readings in Reading; Practice, Theory, Research, 1968; The First R; Readings on Teaching Reading, 1972 "Evaluating the Outcomes of The Social Studies Curriculum" (1936); In Readings in Curriculum Development, 1937 "Evaluation; A Challenge to Progressive Education" (January 16, 1935); In Progressive Education, December 1935; Readings in Curriculum Development, 1937 "Evaluation as a Function of Supervision" (1943); In Elementary School Journal, January 1944 "The Evaluation of Teaching" (1958); In Preparing College Teachers, 1960; Journal of Engineering Education, June 1960; Higher Education in Engineering and Science, 1963 "Evolving a Functional Curriculum" (1951); In American Journal of Nursing, December 1951 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Fa-Ge, "Facing Up to the Big Issues" (January 1953); In Montana Education, January 1953; Ohio Schools, January 1953; Midland Schools, March 1953; Pennsylvania School Journal, March 1954 "The Federal Role in Education" (Winter 1974); In The Great Society; Lessons for the Future, 1974 "The Field of Educational Research" (1965); In Essays on World Education; The Crisis of Supply and Demand, 1969 The Florida Accountability Program (1978); In Today’s Education, September-October 1978 "Forces Redirecting Science Teaching" (October 1962); In Revolution in Teaching; New Theory, Technology, and Curricula, 1964; Secondary Education; A Textbook of Readings, 1966 "General Statement on Evaluation" (March 1942); In Readings in Educational and Psychological Measurement, 1966; Outlines and Readings in Educational Tests and Measurements, 1972 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Ho-Kn, "How Can We Improve High School Teaching?" (September 1948); In Education Digest, December 1948; Wisconsin Journal of Education, November 1949; School and Community, December 1949; Kentucky School Journal, January 1950; Ohio Schools, January 1950; Virginia Journal of Education, March 1950 "Human Behavior; What Are the Implications for Education?" (October 1955); In Readings in Elementary Education, 1961 "The Impact of Students on Schools and Colleges" (1961); In The College Student and His Culture; An Analysis, 1968 "The Importance in Wartime of Co-operation Between Schools and Parents" (February 1943); In University of Chicago Magazine, March 1943 "The Individual in Modern Society" (February 1957); In Contemporary Society; Background for the Instructional Program, 1957 "The Influence of the Curriculum and Teaching on the Development of Creativity" (Spring 1968); In From Learning for Love to Love of Learning; Essays on Psychoanalysis and Education, 1969 "Innovations in Our Schools and Colleges" (1965); In SDC Magazine (System Development Corporation), Winter 1965-66 Institutional Organization of the Behavioral Sciences (1959); In The Behavioral Sciences Today, 1963 "Instructional Technology and the Behavioral Sciences" (October 1967); In Technology in Education; Challenge and Change, 1972 "Investing in Better Schools" (1968); In Needs of Elementary and Secondary Education for the Seventies; A Compendium of Policy Papers, 1970; The Changing High School Curriculum; Readings, 1972 "The Knowledge Explosion; Implications for Secondary Education" (January 1965); In The Changing Secondary School Curriculum; Readings, 1967; Readings in Educational Psychology, 1971; Curriculum Development; Issues and Insights, 1978 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Le-Or, "Learning in America" (November 1977); In Education Digest, January 1978 "Let's Clear the Air on Assessing Education" (February 1966); In Readings in Measurement and Evaluation; Education and Psychology, 1968 "Measuring the Results of College Instruction" (May 11, 1932); In Selected Readings on the Learning Process, 1961 "Meeting the Challenge of the Gifted" (November 1957); In Education Digest, February 1958; Crucial Issues in Education, 1959, 1964 "Modern Aspects of Evaluation" (November 1954); In Educational Psychology; Readings, Supplementary Text, and Study Questions, 1959 "National Assessment; Some Valuable By-Products for Schools" (May 1969); In Readings in Psychological and Educational Testing, 1973 "Needed Research in the Field of Tests and Examinations" (1936); In Educational Research Bulletin, September 16, 1936 "New Criteria for Curriculum Content and Method" (1958); In School Review, Spring 1958 "New Dimensions in Curriculum Development" (September 1966); In Foundations of American Education; Readings, 1969; The Elementary School Principal in Action, 1970 "Next Steps in Improving Secondary Education" (December 1952); In Pupil Appraisal Practices in Secondary School, 1953 "Organization of Learning Experiences" (1950); In Curriculum and Evaluation, 1977 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Pl-Pu, "The Place of Evaluation in Modern Education" (1940); In Elementary School Journal, September 1940; Education Digest, November 1940 "Place of the Textbook in Modern Education" (May 1941); In Ohio Schools, December 1941; Texas Outlook, December 1943 "A Place Where Teachers Learn" (November 1947); In Nebraska Educational Journal, January 1948; Virginia Journal of Education, March 1948 "Prevailing Misconceptions; Some Psychological Misconceptions Which Prevent the Better Adjustment of the College Curriculum" (June 1933); In Bulletin of the American Association of University Professors, October 1933 "A Program of National Assessment" (1966); In Educational Forum, May 1966; National Educational Assessment; Pro and Con, 1966; School Administration; Selected Readings, 1968; Guiding Learning; Readings in Educational Psychology, 1971 "The Purpose and Plan of This Yearbook" (1961); In Minnesota Journal of Education, September 1961; Views on Schooling in America; Current Readings in Education, 1964 "Purposes for Our Schools" (December 1968); In California Elementary Administrator, March 1969; Elementary School Curriculum; An Anthology of Trends and Challenges, 1971; Accountability; Curricular Applications, 1972; Educational Foundations; Ideas and Issues, 1973; Educational Issues of the 70's; Foundations of Education, 1973 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Re-Sp, "Reconstructing the Total Educational Environment" (September 1975); In Curriculum Planning; A New Approach, 1977, 1980 "The Relation of the Curriculum to American Democratic Ideals" (1941); In University of Chicago Magazine, June 1941 Report on Cooperative Education (1961): In Education Digest, December 1961 Research in Science Teaching in a Larger Context (1973): In Journal of Research in Science Teaching, no. 2, 1974 "Resources, Models, and Theory in the Improvement of Research in Science Education" (1966): In Journal of Research in Science Teaching, March 1967 "The Role of the Volunteer" (Winter 1965): In Journal of Cooperative Extension, Fall 1966 "The Role of University Departments of Education in the Preparation of School Administrators" (October 1946): In American Journal of Education, August 1983 "Scholarship and Education for the Professions" (1957); In Journal of Social Work Process, 15, 1966 "Social Forces and Trends" (September 1962); In Education and Society, 1963 "Some Comments on Power and the NAEP" (July 1975); In The Myth of Measurability, 1977 "Some Persistent Questions on the Defining of Objectives" (1964); In Contemporary Thought on Public School Curriculum; Readings, 1968; Behavioral Objectives in Curriculum Development, 1971; Instructional Design; Readings, 1971; Educational Objectives and the Teaching of Educational Psychology, 1972; Curriculum Evaluation; Commentaries on Purpose, Process, Product, 1974 "Specific Approaches to Curriculum Development" (1975); In Curriculum; An Introduction to the Field, 1978; Curriculum and Instruction; Alternatives in Education, 1981 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Te-U.S., "Testing for Accountability" (December 1970); In Education Digest, March 1971; Accountability in American Education, 1972; Accountability for Teachers and School Administrators; Readings in Contemporary Education, 1973; Education and Psychology; Past, Present, and Future, 1973; Educational and Psychological Measurement; Contributions to Theory and Practice, 1975 "Tomorrow's Education" (August-September 1975); In A Nation of Learners, 1976 "Training Administrative Officers for Democratic Leadership" (1939); In American Teacher, February 1940 "Trends in Teaching; How Research Is Affecting Our Understanding of the Learning Process" (May 1951); In Education Digest, September 1951 "Two New Emphases in Curriculum Development" (October 1976); In Education Digest, February 1977 Te-U.S. "The U.S. vs. the World; A Comparison of Educational Performance" (January 1981); In Cream of the Kappan, 1956-1981, 1981; Standard Education Almanac, 1981-1982, 1981 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Wh-Wo, "What Is Behavioral Science?" (August 10, 1956); In Behavioral Science, July 1957 "What Is Supervision?" [1946]; In Western Regional Workshop for Extension Supervisors, [1947] "What Should High Schools Accomplish?" (November 1964); In Education Digest, February 1965 "What Testing Does to Teachers and Students" [1960]; In Testing Problems in Perspective, 1966 "What the Assessment of Education Will Ask" (November 1966); In Readings in Measurement and Evaluation; Education and Psychology, 1968 "What the Curriculum Field Needs to Learn from Its History" (1978); In Journal of Thought, Spring 1986 "Where Learning Happens" (January 1975); In Education Digest, May 1975 "Where We Came Out" (Fall 1962); In The Technological Order, 1963 "Why Evaluate Education?" (February 1972); In Crucial Issues in Testing, 1974 "Words That Do Not Educate" (November 1948); In Secondary Education, November 1948-January 1949, February-March 1949 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 6: Reprints and drafts
    - Various, A-C, "Achievement Testing and Curriculum Construction," reprint ca. 1951, by R. W. Tyler "Cooperation and Conflict in the Mental Development of the Child" Public lecture Nov. 16, 1945 by R. W. Tyler (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Various, C, "Chapter 7. Assessing Intellectual Development Among Diverse Human Beings," by R. W. Tyler in Changing Concepts of Educational Evaluation. "Proposed Abstract. Implications of the Computer for Professional Education," by Ralph W. Tyler (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Various, E, "Effective Learning Experiences Involve Questioning," by R. W. Tyler "Historical Trends in Large-Scale Assessment," by R. W. Tyler (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Various, H-I, "Introduction" to Wilson C. Riles’ No Adversary Situations, An Oral History, by Ralph W. Tyler "Evaluation in Human Resource Development," by Ralph W. Tyler, 1984 (3 copies) (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 7: Speeches and Writings File
    - 1932-1937, Achievement Tests in Colleges and Universities Appraising Progressive Schools, October 24, 1935. Published in Educational Scene. 3 drafts Cooperation of Teachers of the Liberal Arts with Teachers of Education, February, 1934. 2 drafts Defining and Measuring Objectives of Progressive Education. Read at the Fourth Annual Educational Conference, New York City, November 1, 1935. 2 drafts, and a reprint The Development of Examinations at Ohio State University (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - 1932-1937, Discussion of a Theory of Selection of College Students Evaluating the Achievement of College Students. American Association of Junior Colleges, February 23, 1934. Evaluating the Outcomes of Social Studies Curriculum. Chapter for Yearbook, Department of Superintendents, 1936 Evaluating the Work of the Modern School, and A Summary of Evaluating the Work of the Modern School. Evaluation: A Challenge to Progressive Education Evaluation in Thirty Schools (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - 1932-1937, The Evaluation of Professional Training. Paper read at New Orleans meeting of National Education Association, February 20, 1937 Evaluation of Student Achievement in the Physical Sciences The Function of the University in Effecting Major Cultural Transitions, May 29, 1933. Functions of a University How Can We Hope to Evaluate the Outcome of Our Program? How Do Present Measuring Instruments of the School Compare with the Old? Means of Evaluating Accomplishments in English. Fourteenth Ohio State Educational Conference, April 7, 1934. (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - 1932-1937, Measurements, 1932. One handwritten draft, one typed draft, and miscellaneous pages. Measuring the Ability to Interpret Experimental Data Measuring the Effectiveness of Instruction Measuring the Results of College Instruction. Dedication of Graduate Education Building, University of Chicago, March 14, 1932 Methods Used in Improving Tests and Examinations at the Ohio State University (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - 1932-1937, The Objective Examination, Its Development and Application to Nursing Education The Prediction of Milk Production of Cattle. with F. P. Frutchey The Significance of a Comprehensive Testing Program. Reprint and one typed draft. (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - 1932-1937, Some Findings from Studies in the Field of College Biology Some Psychological Misconceptions Which Prevent the Better Adjustment of the High School Curriculum. 2 drafts Some Psychological Misconceptions Which Prevent the Better Adjustment of the College Curriculum. Read at the Progressive Education Association meeting, Chicago, March 3, 1933. 2 drafts and an abstract The Specific Techniques of Investigation (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - 1932-1937, The Study of Adolescent Reading by the Progressive Education Association. Read at University of Chicago, August 13, 1936 A Survey of Present Training Courses for Research Workers. Read at National Education Association, Washington, February, 1932 Techniques for Evaluating Behavior Testing for a Mastery of the Principles of Chemistry Tests in biology. Read at Central Association of Science and Mathematics Teachers, Cleveland, November 25, 1932 To What Degree Can the Content of the Social Studies be Selected on an Objective Basis? 2 drafts (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Outlines of speeches, and notes, 1932-1937 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - 1938-1939, Are Our Schools Adequately Preparing Our Youth for the World of Today? Basic Assumptions which Guide my Work in Educational Measurement. 2 drafts The Classroom of the Future Comprehensive Examination is an Important Aid to Guidance 1 draft, and published copy Cooperation in the Education of Teachers and Administrators Cooperation in the Study of Institutional Problems. Draft and reprint (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - 1938-1939, The Development of a Comprehensive Evaluation Program and Its Use in the Improvement of Instruction Evaluation in a Program of Teacher Education Evaluation in the Field of Guidance Evaluation of Business Education Criteria. Draft and reprint How Can Examining Agencies Improve Their Examining Programs to Make Them More Useful to Schools and Colleges? The Significance of the Nursery School for the University The Thirties in Education-The Years of Questioning (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - 1938-1939, Training Administrative Officers for Democratic Leadership The Training of School Administrators for Effective and Intelligent Service in the School Systems of a Democracy (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - 1940, An Appraisal of Techniques of Evaluation A Comprehensive Evaluation Program and Its Use in Improving Instruction Curriculum Trends in Modern Secondary Schools. 2 drafts Evaluation of Guidance The Future of American Colleges The Future of the Liberal Arts College Governing Ideas-a preface Newer Techniques in Evaluating Growth (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - The Place of Evaluation in Modern Education. 2 drafts, 1940 (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - Principles Involved in Evaluating Student Personnel Services Workshops at the University of Chicago. 2 drafts and 1 reprint, 1940 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - 1941, Contributions of Tests to Research in the Field of Student Personnel Work. 2 drafts Education in Defense of Democracy Educational Adjustments Necessitated by Changing Ideological Concepts (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - 1941, General Statement on Evaluation. Journal of Educational Research Implications of Communications Research for the Public Schools The Influence of Tests on Teaching Methods of Educational Research The Place of the Textbook in Modern Education. 2 drafts and abstract The Relation of Curriculum to American Democratic Ideals. 2 drafts, mimeographed copy, and galley proofs (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - 1941, The Responsibility of College Graduates in a Period of Crisis Some Aspects of General Education [Summary of report presented at meeting of Illinois Federation of Colleges] A Summary of Trends in the Attack on College Instructional Problems (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - 1941, "Outline of Chapter I of the Evaluation Report, Purposes and Procedures of the Evaluation Staff." In Evaluation in the Eight Year Study (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Outlines of Speeches, and notes, 1938-1941 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - 1942, Cooperation in Teacher Education as Related to Our War Effort How Can Democratic attitudes be Developed in Our Pupils? Relations of the Urban Community and the Modern School The Role of Education in our President Emergency (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - 1942, Some Techniques Used in the Follow-up Study of College Success of Graduates of the Thirty Schools Statement for 1942 Yearbook of the Department of Science Instruction Study Guide for the Conference on Guidance (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - 1942, Trends in the Preparation of Teachers (An article about a study of teacher education by the American Council of Education) (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - 1942, "Summary of Statement on the Work of the Department of Education and the Board of Examinations Presented to the Board of Trustees" (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Outlines of speeches, and notes, 1942 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - 1943, Acceptance of Military Experience Toward College Credit Appraisal of Military Training and Experience College Credit for Men in Service The Colleges in Wartime; New Responsibilities; Summary of Conference (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - The Fight Year Study of the Progressive Education Association Homework, Quizzes, and Examinations. 2 drafts, 1943 (Box 70, Folder 12)